第一夜
编剧：史蒂文·莫法特
这裙子可有点大胆啊
The dress is a little daring.
没错 所以我换了这件
Yep, so I went for this instead.
我们要出去玩吗
Are we going out?
家长大人们都在睡觉
Parents are asleep.
风暴监狱住的如何啊
How's Storm Cage?
今晚可是我那12000年终身监禁的第一夜啊
I'm on the first night of 12,000 consecutive life sentences.
目前还不好说 我们去哪儿
Kind of early to say. Where are we going?
卡德伦贝塔星
Alderin Beta.
挺无聊的 到处都是油炸食品店
Boring, planet of the chip shops.
但是 那里有棵高达122米的大树
But there is a 400-foot tree growing out of a clifftop
长在海中央的大山的北门的悬崖边上
on the north side of a mountain in the middle of the sea.
如果你乘坐TARDIS上到顶端
And if you take the lift to the top and look up,
在2360年9月21日凌晨过12分的时刻
at exactly 12 minutes past midnight on the 21 st of September, 2360,
你就会看到全宇宙史上最多的星星
you can see more stars in one sky that at any other moment in the history of the universe.
亮如白昼 非常神奇
It's like daylight, only magic.
你都能借着星光读书了
You could read a book by it.
我不读书的话也没关系吧
Whoo! Is it okay if I don't?
还剩10分钟 快去换衣服
We've got 10 minutes. Get dressed.
这句话差一点就完美了
Oh, that's so close to the perfect sentence.
你带日记本了吗
Did you bring the diary?
这是日记本?
It's a diary?
现在是了 因为 River
It is now, because River,
从现在开始 我们要定下规矩
from now on, there are rules.
喔 你变得好严格啊 我倒也不介意
Ooh, you've gone all strict. Not that I mind.
River 我们两个的顺序完全错乱了
River, you and I, it's all in the wrong order.
我们从不按正常顺序相遇
We never meet in sequence.
你要把所有事都写入日记中
You put everything in the diary
才好确认我们走到哪一步了
so we know where we are.
我能写什么 亲爱的
Put what in the diary? Sweetie,
我可是被关在宇宙最高安保等级监狱里呢
I'm in the highest security prison in all of the known universe.
据说 River Song 能在那个监狱来去自如
River Song could walk in and out of the prison like the walls aren't there.
我就是 River Song
I'm River Song.
那不就行了
Then you'll be fine.
如果你不喜欢这条裙子 衣柜里还多得是
If you don't like the dress, there's plenty more in the wardrobe.
右转再左转 就在那堆乱七八糟的后面
First right, second left, just past the helter-skelter.
River
River!
我就知道你会回来的
I knew you'd come back here,
你这个怀旧的傻瓜
you nostalgic idiot.
抱紧我
Hold me!
River
River!
River?